contracts can receive and send ether by
合同可以通过使用关键字payable来接收和发送以太币，因此在此
using the keyword payable so in this
video I'm gonna give you examples of how
视频，我将为您提供一些示例，说明如何创建应付款功能以及如何
to create payable functions and how to
use payable for addresses and a good way
使用应付帐款作为地址，以及解释这些示例的好方法
to explain about these examples that I'm
about to show you is by building a
即将显示您正在通过建立一个钱包，所以我们要建立一个钱包
wallet so we're gonna build a wallet
that supports depositing ether
支持先存醚再提取醚
withdrawing ether and then also
transferring ether to another address
首先将以太转移到另一个地址，我们将定义一些事件
first we're going to define some events
that will be emitted when we either
当我们存入提款或从中转账时将发出
deposit withdraw or transfer from this
wallet now if you're building the user
现在创建钱包，如果您要在此合同的基础上构建用户界面，则
interface on top of this contract then
emitting the events is essential if you
如果您想实时获取更新，则发出事件是必不可少的
want to get your updates in real time
but for the examples that I'm about to
但对于我要向您展示的示例，我将使用事件来展示
show you I'm gonna use events to show
you some features and solidity that are
您发送和接收以太币时相关的一些功能和坚固性
relevant when you send and receive ether
to a contract when someone deposits into
当某人将钱存入我们的钱包时，我们将要存入一份合同
our wallet we're gonna deposit the
sender of the ether the amount that was
以太币的发送者发送的金额和以太币的总余额
sent and the total balance of the ether
in this contract after the deposit one
在本合同中，入金一提后便要登上这座山
withdrawal were gonna log the mountain
that was withdrawn and the total amount
撤出后，我们做完之后剩下的乙醚总量
of ether that is left after we do the
withdrawal unlike the deposit we don't
提款不同于存款，我们不需要登录发件人的地址，因为
need to log address of the sender since
we only want the owner of this contract
我们只希望该合同的所有者能够撤回，并且最后
to be able to withdraw and the last
event is transfer we're gonna log the
如果是转移，我们将记录我们将加热器发送到的地址
address that we sent the heater to the
Mount and the total balance of ether
挂载和以太转移后的总余额中的第一个功能
after the transfer the first function
that we're gonna define is the deposit
我们要定义的是存款功能，以使该功能能够
function to make this function be able
to receive ether into this contract all
接收以太币到这个合约中，我们要做的就是声明这个功能
we have to do is declare this function
as payable and we're gonna omit the
作为应付款项，我们将省略存款事件的发送者
deposit event the sender of the
transaction will be stored in a global
交易将存储在一个称为消息点发送者的全局变量中
variable called message dot sender
message the value will hold the amount
消息，该值将包含与此一起发送的以太币数量
of ether that was sent with this
transaction and to get the current
交易并获取此合约中以太币的当前余额，您可以
balance of ether in this contract you do
it like this here we're casting this
像这样在这里，我们将其投射到地址中
into address
like where this refers to the contract
就像这里指的是合同，然后在此处访问余额
and then accessing the balance here the
balance is the amount of ether that is
余额是合约中存储在该合约中的以太币数量
stored in this contract after the
deposit so let me give you an example
存入资金，所以让我给您举个例子，假设该合同存储了10个
let's say that this contract stores 10
litres and the generous user calls this
升，慷慨的用户调用此功能发送一个以太消息
function sending one ether so message
that sender will be the address of the
该发件人将是慷慨的用户消息点值的地址，将是
generous user message dot value will be
one liter and the balance will be 11
一公升，因为我们从10乙醚开始，剩下的就是11乙醚
ether since we started out with 10 ether
in this contract and the user sent 1
在此合同中，如果
meter and 10 plus 1 is 11 now if the
function is not marked as payable then
该功能未标记为应付款，那么当您调用此功能时，您将不会
when you call this function you won't be
able to send and either if you do then
能够发送，如果您这样做，则交易将失败，我将向您显示
the transaction will fail and I'll show
you example this later in the video now
您可以稍后在视频中举例说明，现在我们也希望能够存入
we also want to be able to deposit into
this contract when the contract is
该合同在创建合同后即可执行，您可以像这样
created and you can do it like this
similar to the deposit function all you
与存款功能类似，您所要做的就是将构造函数声明为
have to do is declare the constructor as
payable so now when we deploy this
应付的，所以现在当我们部署此合同时，我们可以随其一起发送
contract we can send either with it
again when you don't have the payable
再次，当您没有构造函数的payable关键字时，您
keyword for the constructor then you
won't be able to send an either when you
我们在存入资金后部署此合同时将无法发送任何一个
deploy this contract after we deposit
some meter into this contract later on
稍后，我们将希望能够撤出该合同中的几米
we will want to be able to withdraw from
it so let's create a function to
因此，我们创建一个函数以撤消我们正在输入的其他任何内容
withdraw either further input we're
gonna pass the amount of ether to
要通过以太币提取，我们只想要这个拥有者
withdraw we only want the owner of this
contract to be able to withdraw so let's
合约以能够撤回，因此让我们创建一个函数修饰符，称为
create a function modifier called
only owner the function modifier only
仅拥有者函数修饰符仅拥有者将要求
owner will require that the sender of
the transaction is equal to the owner so
交易等于所有者，因此我们需要定义此所有者
we need to define the owner of this
contract that we're gonna do now up on
我们现在要执行的合同我们定义了一个状态变量，称为
top we define a state variable called
owner and when the contract is deployed
所有者，并且在部署合同后，我们将所有者分配给
we assign the owner to the sender of the
transaction and lastly we append the
交易，最后我们将唯一的所有者修饰符附加到函数中
only owner modifier to the function
withdraw so now this function can only
退出，所以现在该函数只能由所有者调用
be called by the owner
this contract now to send dieter to the
现在将此合同发送给节食者，您称其为功能所有者
owner you call a chance for a function
and passing the amount that we're gonna
并把我们要转给所有者的金额转给您，如果您尝试
transfer to the owner if you try to
compile this you'll get an error saying
编译此内容，您会收到一条错误消息，提示所有者不付款，这是
that the owner is not payable this is
because in order for any address to be
因为为了使任何地址都能收到，您需要
able to receive either you need to
declare as payable so we're gonna do
声明为应付账款，所以我们现在就要做
that right now
and declare the owner as payable now
并在编译时将所有者声明为应付账款，错误将是
when you compile it the error will be
gone after the ether is transferred to
以太转移到捐助者之后消失了，我们将省略提款
donor we're gonna omit the withdrawal
event and we're gonna omit the amount
事件，我们将忽略已提取的金额以及剩余的金额
that was withdrawn and the remaining
ether in this contract after the
以太币在这份合同退出后实际上有三种方式
withdrawal actually there are three ways
to send either to another address which
发送到另一个地址，我将在下一个视频中介绍
I will cover in the next video
so that's withdrawal function next let's
因此，这是取款功能，接下来让我们编写将以太币转移至
write the function to transfer ether to
another address we're gonna name the
另一个地址，我们将命名函数传递，就像
function transfer and like the
withdrawal function we only want the
提取功能，我们只希望合同所有者能够
owner of the contract to be able to
withdraw eager to another address so
急于提款至另一个地址，所以我们将追加唯一的所有者
we're gonna append the only owner
function modifier to this function for
此输入的功能修饰符，我们将输入地址
the input we're gonna person the address
to send the ether to and amount of ether
发送以太币和以太币的发送量类似于我们将以太币发送到的方式
to send similar to how we send ether to
the owner we're gonna send ether to this
我们将通过呼叫将所有者发送以太币到该地址的所有者-点转移和
address by calling - dot transfer and in
order for this address to be able to
为了使该地址能够接收，我们需要将其声明为
receive either we need to declare it as
payable so we're gonna do that right now
应付帐款，所以我们现在就要做，类似于我们将以太币发送到
and similar to how we send ether to the
owner in the withdrawal function here
提款功能的所有者在这里，我们要做的就是调用转账
all we have to do is call the transfer
function on the to address now it's a
上的功能来解决，这有点令人困惑，但是这种转移
little bit confusing but this transfer
function is different from this function
函数与我们在此传输上方定义的函数不同
that we defined above this transfer
function is a built-in function that is
函数是一个内置函数，仅适用于应付账款地址
only available to payable addresses
whereas this transfer function is a
而该传递函数是我们定义并避免的函数
function that we define and to avoid
confusion it might be better to name
混淆，最好将此传递函数命名为
this transfer function
something like transfer eater after the
在功能转移食者后，转移食者之类的东西
function transfers the eater it's going
to omit the transfer event with the
省略转移事件，其地址为我们以金额为单位
address that we centiliter to the amount
and the balance of eater in this
以及转移后的合同中食者的余额，最后
contract after the transfer and lastly
you'll create a helper function so that
您将创建一个辅助函数，以便我们可以检查所存储的食者的余额
we can check the balance of eater stored
in this contract and we've already seen
在此合同中，我们已经在上面的代码中看到了如何执行此操作
how to do this in the code above
so now let's deploy this contract and
现在让我们部署此合同并对其进行测试，注意部署
test it out notice that the deploy
button is red usually it is orange this
按钮通常是红色，这是因为我们将构造函数设为应付款
is because we made a constructor payable
which means that we can send either when
这意味着我们可以在部署此合同时发送
we deploy this contract which is what
we're gonna do now so I'm gonna deploy
我们现在要做，所以我要以100方式部署此合同，
this contract with 100 way and the
balance should now be 100 next
余额现在应该是100，这是该合约的10种存款方式
that's deposit 10 way into this contract
so I'm gonna call the deposit function
所以我要调用存款功能并用它发送10种方式
and send 10 way with it and when we
check the balance it is now a hundred
检查余额，现在已经是一百零一了，我提到您不会
ten earlier I mentioned that you won't
be able to send either to a non payable
能够发送到非付费功能，所以我给你一个
function so let me give you a
demonstration of that here this function
此功能不付款的说明未声明为应付款
not payable is not declared as payable
and when we send some way to it the
当我们向其发送某种方式时，交易应会失败，所以我在这里
transaction should fail so here I'm
gonna send one way and call it not
将发送一种方式，并称它不付款，您可以看到
payable and you can see that the
transaction to the function not payable
交易到不付款的功能失败，这是因为我们尝试发送
failed this is because we try to send
either to a function that is not
要么对未声明为应付款的函数进行下一步，请尝试
declared as payable next let's try the
withdrawal function first I'm going to
提款功能首先，我要在此合约中存入10米，
deposit 10 meter into this contract and
deduct this account by 10 liters
将此账户扣除10升
so now the temp element should be around
所以现在温度元素应该在90左右，接下来我们放一公升
90 next let's deposit one liter we call
that one ether is equal to 10 to the
一个以太币等于18到10的十倍，现在当我们检查城镇时
18th and now when we check our town
balance it should've went up by one
平衡它应该增加一个
which it did
and finally that transfer one liter to
最后将一升转移到第二个帐户，所以我要复制
account number two so I'm gonna copy the
address of account number two switch
第二个帐户的地址切换回第一个帐户，因为
back to account number one because this
is the owner of the contract and only
是合同的所有者，只有所有者才能转让和复制
the owner can transfer and copy the
address of account number two to here
第二个帐户的地址到这里，我们要寄一个以太币
and we're gonna send one ether
[Music]
[音乐]转移后，我们需要检查回来
after the transfer we need to check back
on the account balance of hotel number
在二号酒店的帐户余额中，您可以看到现在是101以太
two you can see that it is now 101 ether
so the transfer was successful so in
因此传输成功，因此在此视频中，我们介绍了如何使用T
this video we went over how to use the T
word payable when you declare a function
当您将某个功能声明为应付款时，应付款一词可以使该功能
as payable then that function can
receive either and when you declare a
接收其中一个，并且当您将构造函数声明为可付款时，则可以发送
constructor as payable then you can send
either when you deploy the contract and
要么在部署合同时发送，要么最后如果您想发送到
finally if you want to send either to
another address then you have to declare
另一个地址，那么您必须声明该地址为应付账款，这就是我的全部
the address as payable well that's all I
got to say about the key word payable in
在下一个视频中必须谈到应付的关键词，我将继续讨论
the next video I'll be talking more
about how to transfer ether to another
关于如何将以太币转移到另一个地址，感谢您的收看
address thanks for watching see you in
the next video and until then have a
下一个视频，直到今天过得愉快
nice day